北川海岸，北韩
PUKCH'ONG COAST, NORTH KOREA
喂，这是怎么回事？我应该要--
Look, what is this? I'm supposed to...
孟谭尚上校总部
北韩非军事区域
Colonel Tan-Sun Moon's H.Q.
De-Militarised Zone
North Korea
打开袋子
Open the bag.
看你还敢不敢训我
That will teach you to lecture me.
芝麻开门
Retract the blast doors.
找个新的心理辅导医生
Find me a new anger therapist.
传送中
我是赵
I am Zao.
你迟到了
You are late.
范彼克先生
久违了
Mr. Van Bierk. I've been looking
forward to this meeting.
幸会
Me too.
孟上校，我非洲的军事伙伴
让我转达他的谢意
My African military friends owe you
many thanks, Colonel Moon.
联合国禁运后
没几个够胆交易叛军钻石
Few men have the guts to trade
conflict diamonds since the U.N. embargo.
联合国的事我还略知一二
我在哈佛和牛津读过
I know all about the U.N.
I studied at Oxford and Harvard.
主修西方伪善
Majored in Western hypocrisy.
从你收藏的车子来看，我可不这么想
From your modest collection of cars,
I wouldn't have guessed.
我要看钻石
Show me the diamonds.
我要看武器
Show me the weapons.
开过来
Bring the weapons.
在非军事区域藏匿武器
Hiding weapons
in the de-militarised zone.
-这儿地雷可不少
-多亏了美国鬼子
- It's a bit of a minefield out there.
- America's cultural contribution.
就算再多地雷
我的气垫船都可在上面漂过
One million landmines. And
my hovercrafts float right over them.
RPG,火焰喷射器
自动武器…
RPGs, flamethrowers,
automatic weapons...
数不尽的弹药
足够发动一场小战争
...and enough ammunition to run
a small war.
我的钻石呢？
My diamonds?
马上检查一遍
Check it over quick.
省着点花
Don't blow it all at once.
这一批货我有特别用途
I have special plans
for this consignment.
他叫詹姆士邦德
英国杀手
His name is James Bond,
a British assassin.
范彼克先生，给你看一样东西
Mr. Van Bierk,
let me show you something.
我们的最新坦克克星
Our new tank buster.
衰变铀炮弹，不二之选
Depleted uranium shells, naturally.
当然了
Naturally.
我看你怎么杀的了我，邦德先生？
And how do you propose to kill me now,
Mr. Bond?
可悲啊，你们英国人还以为
可以对别人指手划脚
It's pathetic that you British still beliee
you have the right to police the world.
你就快要死了
而北韩就快要统一全韩了
You will not live to see the day
all Korea is ruled by the North.
你总算说到点子上去了
Then you and I have something
in common.
是谁？
Who is it?
我儿子在那里？
Where's my son?
是将军
It's the General.
喂，爸爸
Hello... Father.
为什么有火光？
Why is there a fire?
我五分钟后就到
I'll be there in five minutes.
把武器撤走
Get the weapons out of here.
杀了间谍
...and kill the spy.
阿弥陀佛
Saved by the bell.
想不到是白发人送黑发人
My son is dead.
谁与争锋
14个月之后
14 months later
看来你吃了不少苦
I don't condone what they do here.
这事你得问她
Tell it to the concierge.
亏你还笑的出
Still you jest.
死到临头还那么狂妄
Defiant to the last.
他们抛弃了你
Your people have abandoned you.
当你不存在
Your very existence denied.
你却守口如瓶
Why stay silent?
无所谓了
It doesn't matter anymore.
我已经管不了了
Things are out of my hands.
到地头了，邦德先生
We reach the end, Mr. Bond.
你省省吧
Spare me the unpleasantries.
超级强权把韩国一分为二
五十年后…
Fifty years after the superpowers
carved Korea in two...
你出现在北韩
...and then you arrive.
以英国间谍，杀手的身份
A British spy, an assassin.
落了个话柄给强硬派
And now the hard-liners have
their proof.
我们不能相信西方人
We cannot trust the West.
你….
You...
你夺走了我儿子的性命
You took away my son.
他早就该打靶了，我代劳而已
Your firing squad should have done
the job for me.
我本希望西方教育
能让他成为…
I hoped a Western education
would help him become a bridge...
两个世界的桥梁
...between our worlds.
想不到却腐化了他
But all it did was to corrupt him.
过去的就让它过去，好不好？
Let's get this over with, shall we?
我儿子在西方有同党
My son had an ally in the West.
最后一次问你，是谁？
For the last time, who was it?
是谁让他背叛了国家
和他自己的姓氏？
Who made him betray his country
and name?
他也背叛了我
The same person who betrayed me.
转过去
Turn around.
向前走
Start walking.
请继续走
Keep walking, please.
继续走
Keep moving.
赵
Zao.
我被用来交换的…
I'm being traded...
居然是你
...for you.
继续走，请继续走
Keep moving. Keep walking, please.
你总有玩完的时候
Your time will come.
咱们走着瞧
Not as soon as yours.
请继续走
Keep walking, please.
看他那熊样
Look at him.
再次检查
Double check.
你还当他是英雄
You'd think he was some kind
of a hero.
-9号参考资料，帮我查查
-长官
- Reference nine.
- Sir.
第四区
Section four.
好，抓紧他，抓住了
Okay, hold him tight. Got him.
小心他的腿
Watch his legs now.
好，走了
All right, let's go.
初步检查没发现生化物质
他很干净
No biological agents in the prelim scan.
He's clean.
脉搏72，血压120/80
Pulse, 7 2. Blood pressure, 1 20/80.
有神经毒，组织胺
复合胺，酵素抑制剂
Indications of neurotoxins, histamine,
serotonin and enzyme inhibitors.
蝎子毒液
Scorpion venom.
但有也抗毒血清的痕迹
Note also traces of a venom antiserum.
他们先让蝎子蛰他
再为他解毒
They'd sting him
then administer the antidote.
但他的内脏没有受到影响
Yet his internal organs seem unaffected.
肝的状况不太好
但的确是他
Liver not too good.
It's definitely him then.
早
Morning.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
你们真客气
Such hospitality.
你好像不是很高兴看到我
You don't seem too pleased to see me.
如果照我的方式
你现在还在朝鲜
If I'd had my way, you'd still be
in North Korea.
把你赎回来花了我们不少代价
Your freedom came at too high a price.
赵
Zao.
他差点炸了
中国和南韩的高峰会
He tried to blow up a summit
between South Korea and China.
死了三个中国特工才抓到他
Took out three Chinese agents
before he was caught.
现在他自由了
And now he's free.
我从没要求赎我出来
I never asked to be traded.
我情愿死也不想他被放出来
I'd rather die than let him loose.
-你有那个药的
-老早就丢了，这怎么回事？
- You had cyanide.
- Threw it away years ago. What is this?
美国在北韩的高级情报员…
The top American agent...
一周前被处决了
...in the North Korean High Command
was executed a week ago.
美国人从你的监狱里
截听到指证他的讯息
The Americans intercepted a signal
from your prison naming him.
-他们认为是我？
-就你关在那里
- And they think it's me?
- You were the only inmate.
他们认为你吃不了苦头
已经动摇了
They concluded you cracked
and were hemorrhaging information.
我们必须救你出来
We had to get you out.
那你又是怎么想的？
And what do you think?
从你身上残留的药物分析来看
你根本就不知道说过什么
With the drugs they gave you,
you wouldn't know what you said.
我知道规则
I know the rules.
第一条就是，无情
And number one is, no deals.
被抓了就是被遗弃了
Get caught and you're given up.
那次任务出了问题
The mission was compromised.
孟上校接到线报认出了我
Moon got a call exposing me.
连他爸都知道
他在西方有同党
He had a partner in the West.
Even his father knew.
-不管是真是假，都没有关系
-不，有关系
- Whether that's true or not, it's irrelevant.
- No, it isn't.
陷害我的人
再度设计用我来赎出赵
The same person who set me up then
set me up to get Zao out.
我一定要逮到他
So I'm going after him.
你先去福克兰的评估中心
You're going to our evaluation center
in the Falklands.
你的情报员资格已经取消了
Double-O status rescinded.
那我的自由是不是也？
Along with my freedom?
看你的表现再做定夺
For as long as I deem necessary, yes.
你现在是闲人一个
You're no use to anyone now.
心跳
心脏监视器
心跳遂停
-他心跳停了
-拿急救器，通知他的上司
- He's in cardiac arrest.
- Get the crash cart. Notify his superiors.
-心电图没有显示了
-准备
- He's flat-lining on the ECG.
- Stand by.
200焦耳
Two hundred joules.
300焦耳
Three hundred.
再一些阿托品
我们失去他了！准备心脏起搏
Get me some atropine.
We're losing him! Stand by. Clear.
我要出院了
I'm checking out.
谢谢你的救命香吻
Thanks for the kiss of life.
三楼出现安全漏洞
所有人员，红色警戒
Security breach on level three.
All personnel, defensive code red.
使用武力捉拿
Apprehend and detain with force.
三楼出现安全漏洞
所有人员，红色警戒
Security breach on level three.
All personnel, defensive code red.
使用武力捉拿
Apprehend and detain with force.
三楼出现安全漏洞
所有人员，红色警戒
Security breach on level three.
All personnel, defensive code red.
香港游艇俱乐部
我的天，什么人啊这是
My goodness, standards are falling.
领带都不打
No tie, dear me.
套房，跟上次一样
My usual suite, please.
有信用卡吗？
Do you have a credit card?
有行李吗？
Or even any luggage, sir?
邦德先生，真高兴见到你
Mr. Bond, so good to see you.
-好久不见
-陈先生
- It's been a long time.
- Mr. Chang.
总统套房
Open the Presidential Suite.
请我的裁缝过来，顺便带点吃的
Send up my tailor. And some food.
今天的龙虾不错，伴有鹌鹑蛋和海带
The lobster's good, with quails'
eggs and sliced seaweed.
-看看还有没有61年的波林杰酒
-那当然了
- And if there's any left, a '61 Bollinger.
- Of course.
快点搞掂它
Do it... quickly.
最近忙不忙，邦德先生？
Been busy, have we, Mr. Bond?
忙着逃命啊，陈先生
日子不好混啊
Just surviving, Mr. Chang.
Just surviving.
我是安详欲望之泉的按摩师
I am Peaceful Fountains of Desire,
the masseuse.
经理特别关照过的
I come with compliments
of the manager.
我就知道...进来吧
I'm sure you do. Come in.
请到床上去，脸朝下
On the bed, please. Face down.
还象模象样的嘛
Yes, of course.
我可不是随随便便的按摩师
I'm not that kind of masseuse.
我也不是随随便便的大嫖客！
I'm not that kind of customer.
你以为我不知道
你是中国的情报员吗？
You think I haven't always known
you're Chinese Intelligence, Chang?
-香港现在是我们的国土
-别担心
- Hong Kong is our turf now.
- Don't worry about it.
我来这不是想要拿回它
I'm not here to take it back.
手放下来
Put your hands down.
你到底要什么？
What the hell do you want?
帮忙你扳回一城
Just to help you settle a score.
赵杀了你们3个人
Zao killed three of your men.
你安排我进入北韩
我帮你料理他
You get me into North Korea,
I'll take care of him for you.
你又有什么好处？
What's in it for you?
我要报复
Chance to get even.
首先得从赵查起
Zao has information I need.
-我先得请示北京
-去吧
- I'll have to ask Beijing.
- Do it.
请吧
Now get out.
除非你真的想留下来帮我按摩
Unless you really wanna give
me a massage.
邦德先生
Mr. Bond.
我们的一点心意
A little thank-you from us.
古巴？
Cuba?
看来赵先生非常迷恋哈瓦那
It seems Mr. Zao has lost himself
in Havana.
如果你找到他，顺便帮我送送他（上西天）
If you find him, say goodbye from us.
我很乐意
With pleasure.
哈瓦那
HAVANA
我想拿些得雷他多
I'm here to pick up
some Delectados.
得雷他多？我们有30年没做这玩意了
Delectados? We haven't made
Delectados in 30 years.
环球出口
你们老板知道的
Universal Exports.
Check with your boss.
洛….
Raoul...
环球出口
Universal Exports.
请跟我来
Follow me.
您的护照
Your passport, se? Or.
我以为再不会有人抽得雷他多了
I'd come to think the Delectados
would never be smoked.
它们对健康尤其有害，您是…？
They are particularly hazardous
for one's health, Mr...?
邦德
Bond.
邦德先生
Mr. Bond.
你知道为什么吗？
Do you know why?
它是维乐多烟草系列的副产品
It's the addition
of the Volado tobacco.
烧的很慢
Slow burning.
灭的也慢
It never goes out.
就像根废柴（无用的人）
Just like a sleeper.
请恕我冒昧
Sorry for the rude awakening.
我爱我的国家
I love my country.
我从没有要你背叛你的国家
I'd never ask you
to betray your people.
-我在跟一个北韩的
-观光客？
- I'm after a North Korean.
- A tourist?
恐怖份子
A terrorist.
恐怖份子跟自由战士没有区别
各为其主罢了
One man's terrorist is
another man's freedom fighter.
赵可不是什么善男信女
Zao has no interest
in other people's freedom.
我还有几个高层的朋友
I still have some friends
in high places.
该请的请了，该花的花了
Favors called in.
Some dollars spread about.
我们发现你的朋友在这里
在一个岛上
We find your friend is here,
on an island.
在洛斯欧甘诺斯岛
In Los Organos.
那儿有个阿瓦瑞斯医生
经营了一所奇特的诊所
There is a strange clinic
run by Dr. Alvarez.
他研究基因治疗
He leads the field in gene therapy.
来延长我们敬爱领袖的生命
Increasing the life expectancy
of our beloved leaders.
当然还有富有的西方人
And, of course,
the richest Westerners.
赏鸟地图索引
西印度群岛
我们闹革命也许革掉了自由…
We may have lost our freedom
in the revolution...
但却拥有了举世无双的医疗系统
...but we have a health system
second to none.
你好像革命后过得还不错
You didn't do too badly
out of the revolution.
日子总得过下去啊
We all have our ways
of getting by.
你不知道有多少政府官员…
You'd be surprised how many
government officials come to me...
-为了回味过去糜烂的生活来找我
-是啊….
...for reminders of the decadent times.
- Yeah, well...
-借来用用好吗？
-没问题
- Mind if I borrow these?
- Please.
我的线民告诉我
赵是个危险的人物
My sources tell me
this Zao is very dangerous.
我希望我能给你更多的帮助
I wish I could give you more help.
我需要一台好车
I could use a fast car.
请给我一杯魔嘻朵酒
Mojito, por favor.
克鲁格先生
阿瓦瑞斯诊所的出入证
Mr. Krug, your admittance papers
for the Alvarez Clinic.
也该是时候了，费达罗
About bloody time, Fidel.
叫多一点女孩到42号房去
Round up more girls
and take them to room 42.
除非你想成为太监
Unless you want to be known
as Fidel Castrato.
好壮丽的景色
Magnificent view.
可不是吗？
It is, isn't it?
真可惜其他人都没欣赏到
Too bad it's lost on everybody else.
要喝魔嘻朵吗？
Mojito?
试试看
You should try it.
我是珍安辛塔强生
朋友都叫我珍芮（白虎星）
Giacinta Johnson.
My friends call me Jinx.
朋友都叫我詹姆士邦德
My friends call me James Bond.
你说你叫珍芮（白虎星） ？
Jinx, you say?
13号星期五出生的
Born on Friday the 1 3th.
你相信噩运吗？
Do you believe in bad luck?
这么说吧
我的感情关系似乎都不持久
Let's just say my relationships
don't seem to last.
我知道这种感觉
I know the feeling.
掠食者通常都在太阳西下时出现
The predators
usually appear at sunset.
为什么呢？
And why is that?
因为此时他们的猎物出来喝酒
It's when their prey
comes out to drink.
喝的惯吗？
Too strong for you?
我可以学着喜欢它
如果有时间的话
I could learn to like it.
If I had the time.
你有多少时间？
How much time have you got?
到清晨为止，你呢？
Until dawn. What about you?
我来这里赏鸟的
I'm just here for the birds.
鸟类学家
Ornithologist.
嗯，鸟类学家？
Ornithologist, huh?
真会说话咧
Now there's a mouthful.
今晚要忙着找猫头鹰？
So you're gonna be busy tonight
with the owls then?
洛斯欧甘诺斯岛没有猫头鹰
早上之前没有什么可以看的
No owls in Los Organos.
Nothing to see till the morning.
至少外面没有
Not out there anyway.
掠食者…
So, what do predators do...
在太阳下山后做什么呢？
...when the sun goes down?
他们大吃大喝…
They feast...
今朝有酒今朝醉
...like there's no tomorrow.
你一向都是这么好动的吗？
Are you always this frisky?
那种要死要活的感觉
让人回味无穷
I've been missing the touch
of a good woman.
谁要死要活来着？
Who says I'm good?
你要干什么？
What do you want?
-我不需要轮椅
-是吗？
- I don't need a wheelchair.
- No?
现在需要了
You do now.
先生
Se? Or.
-好了
-谢谢
- Okay.
- Gracias.
洛斯欧甘诺斯岛
Isla Los Organos
你要做染色体重置治疗
So you are to have
DNA-replacement therapy.
让我来解释这两个阶段
Let me explain the two phases.
首先，我们要杀死你的骨髓
清除染色体板块
First, we kill off your bone marrow.
Wipe the DNA slate clean.
第二阶段：
Phase two:
引入由健康捐赠人身上
得来的新染色体
Introduction of new DNA
harvested from healthy donors.
孤儿，逃亡者…
Orphans, runaways...
流浪汉
...people that won't be missed.
我觉得我是一位艺术家
I like to think of myself
as an artist.
这就是我创作的时候
And this is when I create.
谢谢
Thank you.
恐怕这是一段痛苦的历程
不过…
It is a painful process,
I'm afraid, but...
百炼始得金嘛
...all great art is.
我很高兴能为你服务
I'll certainly enjoy working on you.
当然，大部分艺术家…
Of course, most artists
are only truly appreciated...
都在他们死后才被尊敬
...after they're dead.
我父亲是一位外科医师
我们住在新罕布夏州
My father was a sergeant.
We lived in Hampshire.
我对乡间的生活有美好的回忆
I have fond memories
of the countryside.
第一阶段完成
第二阶段准备
11号房
很好
Good.
你总算注意到我了
Got your attention.
赵，你整容谁买的单？
Who's bankrolling
your makeover, Zao?
是不是就那个在
北韩陷害我的那个人？
Same person who set me up
in North Korea?
詹姆士？怎么回事？
James? What's going on?
珍芮，赶快离开这里！
快走！快！
Jinx, you gotta get out of here now!
Move! Move!
快走！
Move it!
我们走！
Let's go!
你看，这化学成份显示…
You see, my friend,
the chemical composition shows...
这是狮子山来的叛军钻石
...this is from Sierra Leone.
Conflict diamonds.
这儿有个标记
There's some kind
of marking here.
-“葛”
-我看看
- "GG."
- Let me see.
对
Yes.
是冰岛的葛拉夫企业
From the Graves Corporation
in Iceland.
是他的雷射签名
That's his laser signature.
一位名叫古斯塔夫葛拉夫的人…
A man called Gustav Graves
discovered diamonds there...
一年前在那儿发现了钻石
...a year or so ago.
但它们和叛军钻石完全一样
Yet they're identical
to conflict diamonds.
真是巧合啊
What an amazing coincidence.
你怎么能眼睁睁地看着他…
How can he escape
from a British warship...
从香港港口中央的
英国战舰上逃出来？
...in the middle of Hong Kong
harbor, right under your nose?
-有趣的电台，蒙尼潘妮？
-我听到有暴风雨要来了
- Interesting station, Moneypenny?
- I got a storm warning.
你该把他牢牢看住的…
You were supposed
to throw away the key...
而不是把大门打开
...not leave the door wide open.
你在暗示我和他的脱逃有关？
Are you implying I had a hand
in his escape?
邦德腿跑的可真快，不是吗？
Well, Bond got away real fast,
didn't he?
他要遛的慢了就毕不了业
It is what he's trained to do.
可他手底下可没闲着
Your boy's been very busy.
在古巴烧了一家诊所
He torches a clinic in Cuba.
听着，他要是没有什么好家教…
Listen, you put your house in order...
那我不介意给他上堂课
...or we're gonna do it for you.
先生，您的饮料
Your drink, sir.
幸好我是点的是摇匀的
Lucky I asked for it shaken.
古斯塔夫葛拉夫
钻石之王
-他啥时候来？
-我不知道
- When's he coming?
- I don't know.
-看来他赶不上了
-他正好赶上
- Looks like your man won't make it.
- He's right on time.
今天可是你册封为爵士的大喜日子
Wonderful day to become a knight.
你承认这份荣誉吗？
葛拉夫先生
Will you be using your title,
Mr. Graves?
老实不客气的讲：
我为我现在的身份骄傲
I'm proud of my adopted nation,
but I'd never stand on ceremony.
别出心裁的进场仪式
你该不会奇怪…
After that entrance,
you can't be surprised...
人家说你是爱出风头的“做秀客”吧？
...you're called a self-publicizing
adrenaline junkie, can you?
我更希望我是个“冒险家”
I prefer "adventurer."
我们听说了伊卡鲁斯太空计划
到底是什么呢？
We've heard about the Icarus
space program. What's the secret?
是个惊喜
你们很快就会知道
It's a surprise.
You'll soon be enlightened.
你每天工作24小时
你不需要睡眠的说法是真的吗？
You work 24l7. Is it true
that you don't need sleep?
人生苦短
干嘛浪费时间睡觉？
You get one shot at life.
Why waste it on sleep?
您参加了奥林匹克剑术选拔？
Aren't you trying out for
the Olympic fencing team?
-听说您发狂般地练习
-我一点都不粗鲁
- We hear you're training furiously.
- I never get furious.
就像在击剑中所说的
“分数是什么（有什么用）？”
As they say in fencing,
"What's the point?"
谢谢您
Thank you.
不要让女皇等太久
We don't want to keep Her Majesty
waiting any longer.
-葛拉夫先生
- Mr. Graves.
命中
Hit.
That's a hit.
命中
Hit.
维绿蒂？
Verity?
詹姆士邦德
James Bond.
向您讨教
Your lesson.
花架子倒不错
I see you handle your weapon well.
台上三分钟，台下三年功啊
I have been known
to keep my tip up.
帮个忙好吗？
来时没穿好
Do you mind?
I think I've come undone.
乐意之至
Why not?
命中，就位，开始
Hit. Positions. Play.
好好瞧瞧我们这最棒的
Feast your eyes
on the finest blade in the club.
古斯塔夫葛拉夫？
Gustav Graves?
他的公关，米兰达佛洛斯特
His publicist, Miranda Frost.
我的得意门生
她很棒，对不？
My protégé.
Gorgeous, isn't she?
她在悉尼拿过金牌
She took the gold at Sydney.
-是晋位的，如果没记错的话
-晋位？
- By default, if I remember.
- Default?
打败她的那个家伙
类固醇用药过量
The one who beat her
OD'd on steroids.
米兰达的金牌当之无愧
Miranda deserved that gold.
于是她现在教葛拉夫如何赢得金牌
Now she's teaching Graves
how to win one.
他只为利而战
He only plays for cash.
他在这通杀四方，独孤求败
He's won so much,
nobody else wants to fight him.
要不要见个面？
You wanna meet him?
那是
Absolutely.
劳驾
Lead on.
-葛拉夫？
-维绿蒂
- Gustav?
- Verity.
-您是…？
-邦德
- And Mr...?
- Bond.
詹姆士邦德
James Bond.
-我们见过吗？
-如果有我会记得的
- Have we met before?
- I think I'd remember.
当然，是我弄错了
Of course you would. My mistake.
-邦德先生，你赌不赌？
-那得看赌什么了
- Are you a gambling man, Mr. Bond?
- If the stakes are right.
一分一千元
会不会太多？
A thousand a point
too much for you?
维绿蒂，要下注吗？
Care to place a bet, Verity?
不，谢了
No, thanks.
我不喜欢看斗鸡
I don't like cockfights.
开始吧？
Shall we?
失陪了
Excuse me.
三战两胜？
Best of three hits?
就位
Positions.
准备，开始
Ready. Play.
小心了
En garde.
命中
Hit.
就位
Positions.
开始
Play.
命中
Hit.
2比0
Two-nil.
还要继续吗？
Do you want to continue?
-要不要加注？
-你有几个钱？
- You wanna up the wager?
- How much can you afford?
就赌这个
Let's play for this.
我在古巴拿到的
I picked it up in Cuba.
相信是你的物产
I believe it's one of yours.
哼哼，硬通货
My, my. They do get around.
钻石人人爱
But then diamonds are for everyone.
精品之选，完美无瑕
Brilliant specimen.
Completely flawless.
就象非洲叛军钻石那样
And chemically identical
to African conflict diamonds.
你会输的很惨
Then you're about to lose
something very precious.
就位
Positions.
准备
Ready.
-开始
-小心了
- Play.
- En garde.
噢，亲爱的
Oh, dear.
还要来吗？
You want to continue?
今天我不见红就不罢休！
Of course I want to bloody continue!
既然我们已经加码…
But since we're upping the wager...
干脆就玩大点，你敢吗？
...let's up the weapons,
shall we?
老规矩，谁见红谁就输
Let's do this the old-fashioned way.
First blood drawn from the torso.
够了！
That is enough!
米兰达，我们松松筋骨而已
It's just a little sport, Miranda.
看来还是你占了上风，邦德先生
Seems you beat me, Mr. Bond.
我们去楼下办手续吧？
Settle downstairs, shall we?
你是个难得的对手，邦德先生
You're a rare challenge, Mr. Bond.
这个周末我在冰岛有个科技展
关于“伊卡鲁斯”的
I'm putting on a scientific demonstration
in Iceland at the weekend. Icarus?
想必你有兴趣
米兰达，安排一下
Perhaps you could join us.
Miranda, make the arrangements.
先让我把这烂摊子收拾好再说吧
Once I've smoothed things over
with the club.
真不敢想象没有你我该怎么办？
What would I do without you?
你说我们两个在冰岛会不会重逢呢？
Can I expect the pleasure of you
in Iceland?
你死了这条心吧
I'm afraid you'll never
have that pleasure.
邦德指挥官
有人让我把这个交给您
Excuse me, Commander Bond.
Someone left this for you.
这里是该重新装璜了
Place needed redecorating anyway.
我听说过这个地方
I heard of this place.
从没想到有一天我也会在这里
Never thought I'd find myself here.
有些事还是不知道的好
Some things are best kept underground.
废弃的车站，废弃的情报员
An abandoned station
for abandoned agents.
-你的请柬
-你在葛拉夫身上查到什么？
- Your calling card.
- So, what have you got on Graves?
你陷我于不义…
You burn me...
-现在却要我帮你？
-你想我道歉？
...and now you want my help?
- Did you expect an apology?
我知道你为求任务完成
会不惜一切
I know you'll do whatever
it takes to get the job done.
-就像你一样
-不同的是，我不会妥协
- Just like you.
- The difference is, I won't compromise.
你不能要求我每样事情都做到黑白分明
Well, I don't have the luxury of
seeing things as black and white.
-你走后，我们都变了
-我没有
- While you were away, the world changed.
- Not for me.
你在怀疑葛拉夫
不然你也不会叫我过来
You're suspicious of Graves,
or I wouldn't be here right now.
-你查到什么？
-除了本他的自传外一无所知
- So, what do you have?
- Nothing beyond the official biography.
在钻石矿工作的孤儿…
Orphan working in a diamond mine...
主修工程，在冰岛找到钻石
把一半捐给慈善团体
...learns engineering, makes a huge find
in Iceland and gives half of it to charity.
一夕之间
从一无所有到拥有一切
From nothing to everything
in no time at all.
-科技展是在是这个周末吗？
-不过是他又一个炒作噱头
- And his demonstration this weekend?
- Probably just another publicity stunt.
告诉我古巴诊所的事
Tell me what you know
about this Cuban clinic.
基因治疗
Gene therapy.
用染色体移植产生新的身份
New identities courtesy
of DNA transplants.
所谓的“美容院”我倒是听说过
想不到是真的
So-called "beauty parlor." We'd heard
rumors. I didn't think it really existed.
都不重要了
It doesn't anymore.
赵逃走了
不过他留下这些
Zao got away,
but he left these behind.
全是葛拉夫矿里来的
All from Gustav Graves' mine.
我认为葛拉夫的矿只是个幌子
卖的全是非洲叛军钻石
I think it's a front for laundering
African conflict diamonds.
我们查证要很小心
葛拉夫买通了很多官员
We need to tread carefully.
Graves is politically connected.
光脚的不怕穿鞋的
Lucky I'm on the outside, then.
看来你又咸鱼翻生了
It seems you've become useful again.
你是该恢复我的工作了
Then maybe it's time
you let me get on with my job.
请原谅我的坦白：
哪有打工的…
Forgive my mentioning it,
but a perfect marksman...
把枪口对准老板的
...isn't really supposed
to shoot his own boss.
你可以倒回去看
Check the replay.
你会发现他死了
而她只是一点皮外伤
You'll find he's dead and
she's only got a flesh wound.
你总有借口是不是，零零零？
There's always an excuse,
isn't there, double-O zero?
你要不信我的枪法
我可以去靶场证明给你看
Give me the old firing range any day.
可这不是靶场
你要适应新方法
Yes, but it's called the future,
so get used to it.
这儿就是你们扔垃圾的地方？
So this is where they keep
the old relics, then, eh?
这儿是我们开发尖端科技的地方
This is where our most cutting-edge
technology is developed.
-懂了
-你非得这么好奇吗？
- Point taken.
- Must you touch everything?
这个还能用吗？
Does this still work?
-听着….
-尖端科技“尖”在哪儿？
- Now, look...
- So where is this cutting-edge stuff?
我正要说到
I'm trying to get to it.
把枪给我
Weapon, please.
一片安全玻璃
一只普通的戒指
One pane unbreakable glass,
one standard-issue ring finger.
转一下…哇啦
Twist so. Voilà.
超高频单音振动器
Ultra-high frequency
single-digit sonic agitator unit.
-你的聪明盖过了你的样貌
-我比你想象中还要聪明…
- You're cleverer than you look.
- Better than looking cleverer...
包括你。跟我来
...than you are. Follow me.
给你的新表
我相信这是第20只了
Now, a new watch.
This will be your 20th, I believe.
-时间过得真快
-是啊，007…
- How time flies.
- Yes, well, 007...
过去的这么多年里
你从没还过我表
...why don't you establish a record
by returning this one.
你的新座骑
Your new transportation.
-也许你干活太累了
-英国顶尖的工程科技
- Maybe you've been down here too long.
- The ultimate in British engineering.
-你是在拿我开涮吧
-我跟我的前任一样…
- You must be joking.
- As I learned from my predecessor...
工作十分严谨
...I never joke about my work.
奥斯顿马丁叫它“反窥视”
我们称它做“反凝视”
Aston Martin call it the Vanquish,
we call it the Vanish.
-很好
-自适应伪装
- Very good.
- Adaptive camouflage.
我们用微型摄像机把周围的环境
Tiny cameras project
the image they see...
投影到车身的发光聚合物表皮上
...onto a light-emitting polymer skin
on the opposite side.
一般人不仔细看是看不出来的
再加上几个精心设计：
To the casual eye, as good as invisible.
Plus, the usual refinements:
弹射椅，鱼雷，自锁定机枪
可用以射击移动的目标
Ejector seat, torpedoes, target-seeking
shotguns to shoot down mobile objects.
这是说明书，顶多两个钟头你就能搞掂它
The manual. Should be able to
shoot through that in a couple of hours.
Q，只要几秒钟就搞掂了
Just took a few seconds, Q.
我如果能让你也消失就好了
Wish I could make you vanish.
进来
Come in.
如果你执意要去冰岛执行任务…
Before you leave on your mission
for Iceland...
告诉我你是怎么看詹姆士邦德的
...tell me what you know
of James Bond.
他是零零情报员
我今天才发现他是特狂野的那种
He's a double-O.
A wild one, as I discovered today.
他喜欢火上浇油…
He'll light the fuse
on any explosive situation...
累己累人，草菅人命
...and be a danger to himself and others.
Kill first, ask questions later.
挑衅，好战
一个冷面杀手
His method is to provoke and confront.
A man nobody can get close to.
一个花花公子
A womanizer.
你在冰岛跟他碰头的机会很多
You're going to be seeing
a lot more of him in Iceland.
我很尊重您的意旨
但他可能会暴露我的身份
With great respect,
a man like him could blow my cover.
你自愿做这个案子
但三个月来几乎没什么成果
You volunteered for this, but in three
months, you've found next to nothing.
葛拉夫看来没什么问题
Graves seems to be clean.
邦德不这么认为
所以我想让他象你所说的那样：
Bond thinks differently, so I'm going to
let him do what you so ably described:
去葛拉夫先生那里搅局
你在那里…
Mix things up a little with Mr. Graves.
With you there...
正好让事情不会失控
...things won't get out of hand.
过去三年你做密码研究时
工作和私人生活分开得很清楚
In your three years in Cryptology, you've
kept business and pleasure separate.
并没和任何同事发生纠葛
即使有好几次别人追求你
You haven't fraternized with any of your
fellow agents, despite several advances.
和同一个圈子里的人交往
是非常不智的
It would be foolish to get involved
with someone within the community.
尤其是詹姆士邦德
Especially James Bond.
我是奇尔先生（音同杀）
I'm Mr. Kil.
真是个死而无憾的好名字
Well, there's a name to die for.
时速324里，新的个人最好纪录
Three hundred and twenty-four
miles an hour. A new personal best.
第二推进器又坏了
修好它
Thruster two cut out again.
Get it fixed.
-很高兴你能来，羡慕我吗？
-我羡慕你可以死的快
- Glad you could make it. Like my run?
- You were on the edge of losing control.
只有在生与死的边缘我们才能
真正认清自己，褪下伪装
It's only by being on the edge that we
know who we really are. Under the skin.
拿唐诺坎贝尔1967年的“青鸟”为例
他创下了水上纪录
Take your Donald Campbell.
1967, the Bluebird. Water speed record.
-没到第二圈他就挂了
-但他拼了命是在追寻自己的梦想
- Campbell died on his return run.
- But he died chasing a dream.
-人不也该这样的嘛？
-死活我也不去
- Isn't that the way to go?
- I'd rather not go at all.
-追寻梦想不如创造梦想
-不睡觉的好处之一
- You don't chase dreams, you live them.
- A virtue of never sleeping.
就是我必须创造我的梦想
再说，死后你想不睡都难
I have to live my dreams. Besides,
plenty of time to sleep when you're dead.
邦德先生
Mr. Bond.
-佛洛斯特小姐
-我带您去您的房间
- Miss Frost.
- I'll show you your room.
冰的殿堂，你有没有家的感觉？
A palace of ice.
You must feel right at home.
这是为了今晚的演示而建造的
This was built
for tonight's demonstration.
人们既能观赏到火爆的演出
同时也能感受到冰冷的舒适
The human element necessitates
a balance of heat and cold.
那为什么建在湖上？
希望葛拉夫选错址
Built on a lake?
Hope Graves got things right.
-隔壁是什么？
-钻石矿
- What's that property next door?
- The diamond mine.
和葛拉夫先生的住处
And Gustav's living quarters.
谢谢
Thank you.
你的房间
This is you.
太好了
还有什么要交待的吗？
Wonderful.
Would you like to show me more?
伏特加马丁尼
加多点冰，如果你不介意的话
Vodka martini.
Plenty of ice, if you can spare it.
魔嘻朵？
Mojito?
詹姆士，来赏企鹅吗？
James. Here for the penguins this time?
-还是又来赏景的？
-我只对濒临绝种的动物有兴趣
- Or for the view again?
- I'm only interested in endangered species.
那么，包括我吗？
Well, does that include me?
-那得看这次你又想干什么
-上次我在危急关头舍你而去
- Depends on what you're up to this time.
- So I left you in an explosive situation.
是因为你这么本事肯定不用我照顾的
Figured you could handle yourself.
-难怪你的感情关系都不持久
-我只是不喜欢有人碍手碍脚
- No wonder your relationships don't last.
- I just don't like to get tied down.
你看起来气色真差
You look terrible.
你也好不到哪去
You aren't looking too good yourself.
-还有副作用吗？
-我老是睡不着
- You're still feeling the side effects?
- The insomnia is permanent for me.
这玩意可让我短时间恢复精力
An hour on the Dream Machine
keeps me sane.
-怎么会这样？
-邦德
- What happened to you?
- Bond.
他什么都不知道
我和他距离这么近…
He knows nothing.
I've been this close to him...
他却不知道我到底是谁
...and he didn't know
who I really was.
-在易容之后你见过我父亲？
-是的
- You saw my father after your exchange?
- Yes.
-孟将军仍在哀悼你的不幸
-我的不幸
- General Moon still mourns your death.
- My death.
邦德先生
Mr. Bond.
-你是…？
-史威夫,太空科技杂志社的
- And Miss...?
- Swift. Space and Technology magazine.
是吗？邦德先生有没有跟你吹
他的“大爆炸”理论？
Really? I take it Mr. Bond's been
explaining his big-bang theory?
-啊对，我想我已经被感动了
-看出来了
- Yeah, I think I got the thrust of it.
- I see.
演示会五分钟后就要开始了
走吧
The demonstration's about
to begin in five minutes. Shall we?
走吧
Shall we?
-怎么不是珍芮（白虎星）？
-我什么时候都是你的白虎星
- Not "Jinx" anymore?
- I'll always be a jinx to you.
我一直都在努力
试着回报这片土地…
I'm always trying to give the planet
something in return...
生我养我的土地：
...for what it has given me:
因为赐给了我宝贵的钻石
Those little shards of heaven
known as diamonds.
钻石不仅仅是块值钱的石头
它们是梦想
Diamonds aren't just expensive stones.
They are the stuff of dreams.
有了它就可梦想成真
And the means to make dreams real.
想像一下：
这个世界灿烂光明…
Imagine being able to bring light and
warmth to the darkest parts of the world...
百姓五谷丰登
人民丰衣足食
...being able to grow crops year-round,
bringing an end to hunger.
想像一下又一颗太阳…
Imagine a second sun...
如钻石一般闪耀在天空
...shining like a diamond in the sky.
光芒四射
Let there be light.
向您呈现伊卡鲁斯！
I give you Icarus!
伊卡鲁斯的设计非常独特的，
它的银色外皮能吸收太阳光…
Icarus is unique. Its miraculous
silver skin will inhale the sun's light...
再慢慢的散发到地球表面
...and breathe it gently
upon the Earth's surface.
你们想像不到伊卡鲁斯
将会如何改变你的生活
You have no idea how much Icarus
is about to change your world.
让我们用内心的狂热
去闪耀美丽的夜晚
And now let us brighten this night
with our inner radiance.
好了，可以收工了
All right, that's a wrap.
-小毛，给我看看你改的怎么样了
-是
- Vlad, show me the modifications.
- Yeah.
这是你要我加进去的自卫装置
Here is the self-defense mechanism
you asked me to build in.
-5万伏特？
-十万
- Fifty-thousand volts?
- A hundred.
用起来…
Armed...
-不是很危险？
-非常危险
...and very dangerous.
- Very.
高压回流阀
警告！
进汽阀未关闭前
请勿关闭
入侵警告！
日防夜防，家贼难防
M warned me this would happen.
我就知道是M在背后搞鬼
That's why you tried
not to be interested in me.
老天
你比传说中还更衰格
God, you're even worse
than your file says.
做戏就要做全套
They don't look too convinced.
加油，更要毫无保留
Come on, put your back into it.
你有什么花花肠子我一清二楚
你一点安全感都没有
I know all about you. Sex for dinner, death
for breakfast. Not gonna work with me.
-没有？
-没有
- No?
- No.
-可是你现在很享受嗳
-住口，你想吃豆腐吃到什么时候？
- You're getting good at this.
- Stop it. Are we still being watched?
-他们老早就走开了
-老天，真受不了你
- They left ages ago.
- God, you're impossible.
我们走
Let's get out of here.
你既然对我这么有兴趣
干脆留下来好了
You'd better stay here.
Keep up the charade of being lovers.
行
All right.
你那毛糙的性格有进步嘛，
足足两小时过后你才开始捣乱
I admire your restraint. You were here
a full two hours before anything blew up.
你再这样下去我们两个迟早得完蛋
The way you're going,
you'll get us both killed.
詹姆士
告诉你在北韩怎么了
James, tell me what really happened
in North Korea.
我被出卖了
I was betrayed.
就这样
That was all.
这就是江湖
Occupational hazard.
天，枉你还是零零情报员
This is crazy. You're a double-O.
那都素些浮云
It's only a number.
詹姆士…
James...
小心点
...be careful.
回到你房间
我会回来找你的
Go back to your room.
I'll come back for you.
你为什么要“杀”我？
Why do you want to kill me?
准确的说是“人道毁灭”
I thought it was
the humane thing to do.
谁派你来的？
Who sent you?
你妈
Your mama.
她要我转达她对你是多么的失望
And she's really disappointed in you.
我就告诉你吧
I'll let you in on a little secret.
这个矿是蒙人的，但这个镭射刀…
This mine is fake, but the lasers...
却是杀人的
...are real.
她不肯说
She won't talk.
那她以后也不用说了
Let's make it permanent.
我习惯用刀
I'll use the laser.
手脚干净点
Don't leave a mess.
-珍芮？
-詹姆士！快！
- Jinx?
- James! James! No, no!
快关掉它！
Turn it off! Off! Off!
詹姆士，打扰一下
James, I could use a little help here.
快关掉它…
Switch it off...
不然我就要被大卸八块了
...or I'll be half the girl
I used to be.
记得有人说我碍手碍脚来着？
So, the girl who hates
to be tied down, huh?
你要不要放我下来吗？
Are you gonna get me off this?
-你哪格庙的，中情局？
-国家安全局
- What are you, CIA?
- NSA.
-我们一条船上的
-却是同船（床）异梦
- We're on the same side.
- Doesn't mean we're after the same thing.
错，世界和平，爱满人间…
是我们共同的梦想
Sure it does.
World peace, unconditional love...
当然，还有这位
一脸富贵相的小“痘痘”
...and our little friend
with the expensive acne.
-赵？
-对，是他
- Zao?
- Yeah, Zao.
他回那边去了
还有那个诡异迷幻面具
He's back there with some weird,
psychedelic light mask.
可能是从古巴诊所带回来的
Probably brought it from the clinic
in Cuba.
不可能是他带回来的
He couldn't have brought it.
那个东西本来就是这里的
It was already here.
它属于另一个韩国人
It belongs to another Korean.
他的上司
His boss.
-我们需要奇尔的指纹来开门
-我有更好的主意
- We need Kil to help us get out of here.
- I got a better idea.
使用者代号
身份无误
-我要去寻求支援
-等一下
- I'm going to get backup.
- Wait.
先去找米兰达，她是MI 6号
叫她先离开
Go to Miranda first. She's MI6.
Warn her to get out.
那你有什么打算？
And what are you gonna do?
我还有事要做
Unfinished business.
你苟延残喘就是为了挑个黄道吉日…
So you live to die another day...
是吗，上校？
...colonel.
很好，我还以为你做梦都想不到呢
At last. I was beginning to think
you'd never guess.
痛不痛？
Was it painful?
-基因治疗？
-你无法想像
- The gene therapy?
- You couldn't possibly imagine.
很好，这下我放心了
Good. I'm glad to hear that.
吃得苦中苦，方为人上人
But there have been compensations.
把你当猴耍玩玩也不错
Like watching you flail around
in your ignorance.
老鼠没有被玩够
猫咪是不急于吞下肚的
Granting you life just to see
if you'd get wise.
我玩的挺开心的
It's been fun.
不好意思，
快乐的时光总是那么短暂
Well, the fun is about to come
to a dead end.
你我打交道的时间不长…
We only met briefly, you and I...
却给我留下了难以磨灭的印象
...but you left a lasting impression.
当我重获新生，重新做人的时候…
When you forced me to present
the world with a new face...
我就刻意的在模仿你
...I chose to model the disgusting
Gustav Graves on you.
详细点来说
Just in the details.
就是话中有话，模棱两可
That unjustifiable swagger.
莫名其妙，胸无点墨
Your crass quips, a defense mechanism
concealing such inadequacy.
我喝的墨水全灌这里了
My defense mechanism is right here.
看来，佛洛斯特小姐也不简单啊
So, Miss Frost is not all she seems.
不要以貌取人
Looks can be deceptive.
是的
Yes.
知道是谁在北韩出卖你吗？
Did you find out who betrayed you
in North Korea?
迟早的事
Only a matter of time.
就没想过是内鬼所为？
You never thought of looking
inside your own organization?
远在天边，近在眼前
She was right under your nose.
睡觉也带着枪是个好习惯
It was so good of you
to bring your gun to bed.
没办法，江湖险恶
Yes. Occupational hazard.
你知道，我有一种天赋
You see, I have a gift.
可以察知别人弱点
An instinct for sensing
people's weaknesses.
你的弱点是“女人”，她和我的
弱点是“必胜”
Yours is women. Hers and mine
is winning, whatever the cost.
在悉尼我使计把她扶上金牌奖座…
When I arranged for the fatal overdose
of the true victor at Sydney...
现在她则成了我专用的
MI 6号情报员…
...I won myself
my very own MI6 agent...
想怎么用就怎么用：
她的智慧，她的天才…
...using everything at my disposal:
her brains, her talent...
甚至是她的肉体
...even her sex.
女人的致命武器
The coldest weapon of all.
哈
Hello.
米兰达？
Miranda?
杀了我一个，还有后来人
There will be others after me.
你是说你的美国朋友，珍芮
You mean your American friend, Jinx.
又一个无辜者
Soon to be the victim of a tragedy.
-这儿看似宫殿其实却是地狱
-除下你的设备
- An ice palace can be a treacherous place.
- Hand over the toys.
行，没问题
Oh, yeah.
你知道吗，我爱死你的“大麻子”了
You know, I've missed
your sparkling personality.
临死还嘴硬？
How's that for a punch line?
杀了他
Kill him.
邦，昨晚真是棒…
I enjoyed last night, James...
不过你真的没有安全感
...but it really is death for breakfast.
杀了他，不要声张
Kill him, quietly.
快动手！
Kill him. Now!
-他逃掉了
-没有关系
- He got away.
- No matter.
猫嬉老鼠乐趣多多
The pleasure of the kill
is in the chase.
请将军过来
Bring me the generals.
诸位…
Gentlemen...
我答应会演示给你们看的
...I promised you a demonstration.
现在你将要看到
伊卡鲁斯真正的威力
Now you will see the true power
of Icarus.
西方间谍逃得了一时
但他躲不过一世
The Western spy runs,
but he cannot hide.
伊卡鲁斯能锁住发热方位
然后聚焦太阳能
Icarus will lock on to the heat signature
and concentrate the sun's power.
老板，他破了你的记录
Hey, boss, he beat your time.
我要切下这一整块
Time to draw the line.
全球变暖真的很可怕的
Global warming is a terrible thing.
好身手，和邦德一样
Yeah, nice moves, just like Bond.
他昨晚也是一样强劲有力
He was pretty vigorous last night
as well.
他上了你？
He did you?
-想不到他会饥不择食
-他不会看上你的
- I didn't know he was that desperate.
- He's not coming for you.
他现在跑的比谁都快
He just died running,
trying to save his own skin.
好料子
That's pretty good tailoring.
希望湿了以后不会缩水
I hope it doesn't shrink
when it gets wet.
我们很快就会成功
Soon, we will be victorious.
一小时后动身，快去做准备
We've got one hour to wrap this up.
Let's move.
珍芮，你在那里？
Come on, Jinx, where are you?
所有单位向我报告！
All units report. Now!
警告，自适应伪装失败
Warning, adaptive camouflage failure.
是时候给美国人洗澡了
Time to give the American her bath.
顺应伪装修复
Adaptive camouflage restored.
小毛，什么叫“人体工程学”？
Vlad, does the word "ergonomics"
mean anything to you?
以人为本？还是机器为本？
Man? Machine?
怎么看都象个手提箱
This is still a suitcase.
给我造个相衬的外形
Finish it, will you?
快点，这里很暖的
快呀
Come on, it's warm in here.
Come on.
低温可以保持生命，对不对？
快点给我醒过来啊
The cold kept you alive, huh?
It must've kept you alive.
快点
Come on.
你怎么这么久才来？
What took you so long?
对不起
I'm sorry.
美国指挥部
非军事区域，南韩
约翰探员
Agent Johnson.
-詹姆士
-查尔斯
- James.
- Charles.
好吧，我们长话短说，直奔主题
Okay, bring us up to speed on this.
非军事区域北面有另一个部队集结
已经有8万人并在增加中
Another division mobilized north
of the DMZ. 80,000 troops and counting.
-另有一百万军力储备
-孟的父亲不主张打仗
- And another million in reserve.
- Moon's father won't allow a war.
孟将军被捕了，强硬派是主谋
General Moon's under arrest.
Hard-liners staged a coup.
你故意陷邦德入罪来误导我
You deliberately misled me
by implicating Bond.
-如果你早告诉我你的情报员--
-她早就死了
- If you'd told us about your agent...
- She'd be dead.
-你的地下组织已经证实了
-我们哪有什么地下组织…
- Your mole would've made sure.
- We wouldn't have a mole...
如果你早告诉我们佛洛斯特
和孟都在哈佛的剑术队
...if you'd told us that Frost and Moon
were on the Harvard fencing team together.
我们这行最重要的是知道要信任谁
Knowing who to trust
is everything in this business.
好啊，詹姆士庞德
Well, well, James Bond.
-正赶上看烟火表演
-严肃点，谈正事
- Just in time for the fireworks.
- Let's get down to business.
我们在二区
We're at DEFCON 2.
如果北韩南进
他们会大举入侵
And if the North goes south,
they're gonna go south big-time.
但是中间有个雷区
You don't just stroll through
a minefield.
他们会另辟蹊径
You need some kind of an edge.
-伊卡鲁斯
-我们已经注意到了…
- Icarus.
- We're taking care of that...
反卫星武器会在一小时内发射
...with an ASAT launch in one hour.
-葛拉夫在那里？
-在北韩的一个空军基地
- Where's Graves?
- In a North Korean air base.
我们现在对他无可奈何
They're right where we can't touch him.
那是你…
You can't...
-不包括我
-听着…
...but I can.
- Look...
我们在这里预防事情发生
不是来确定事情发生
...we're here in case things escalate,
not to make sure that they do.
不能入侵北韩
总统直接指示我的
No incursions into the North.
President gave me a direct order.
别拿根鸡毛当令箭
And when did that ever stop you?
你爱去不去拉倒
我会派007去
You make your own decision.
I'm sending in 007.
那我这张老脸往哪搁？
You think I'd leave this
in the hands of the British?
你和他一起去
You go with him.
接近降落地带
Approaching drop zone.
好，走了！
Okay, let's go!
-他们已经进入北韩空域
-别担心，罗宝逊
- They've entered North Korean airspace.
- Relax, Robinson.
我们的雷达看不到的话
北韩人更看不到的
If our radar can't see those switchblades,
the North Koreans sure as hell can't.
平壤空军基地，北韩
老板，他们向伊卡鲁斯射击
Hey, boss, they launched
against Icarus.
开启自动模式
Leave it on automatic.
听说过高射炮打蚊子，
可没见过发射火箭去打镜子
I hope nobody here is superstitious.
That's one big mirror we're about to break.
我的天
Oh, my God.
集结南韩部队，替我接总统
Mobilize the South Korean troops.
And get me the president, now!
还没有邦德的消息？
Still no news of Bond?
有车过来了
Vehicles.
还有一些大人物
Some big shots.
是他
It's him.
-300米
-偏差，1.5
- Three hundred meters.
- Windage, one and a half.
我们必须登上那台飞机
We gotta get on that plane.
你，请我父亲下来
You, have my father brought down.
爸爸…
Father...
很抱歉我们以这样的方式见面
...I regret our meeting had to be like this.
你认不出是我？
You can't tell it's me?
我不认识你
I don't know you.
你一直很难接受我
You've always found it difficult
to accept me.
这样可能让你更容易忘却…
That made my exile easier to bear...
但我从没忘记你教过我的
...but I never forgot
what you taught me.
战争讲究谋略，
In war, the victorious strategist
only seeks battle...
然后才是战备
...after the victory has been won.
你看，爸爸
我的功课没落下…
You see, Father, I remember
my Art of War...
这就是致胜的法宝
...and this is what guarantees
that victory.
儿子啊…
My son...
你到底怎么了？
What have you done to yourself?
来，爸爸
Come, Father.
看看你儿子多了不起
Watch the rising of your son.
他要是敢动三八线…
The second that hits
the 38th parallel...
老子就跟他玩命
...hit them with
everything we got.
你玩他不过
That may not be enough.
看到了吗，爸爸？
Do you see, Father?
伊卡鲁斯还可以扫雷…
Icarus is clearing the minefield...
从此我们踏上了康庄大道
...creating a highway for our troops.
美国佬再不滚蛋，就等着收尸吧
If the Americans don't run,
Icarus will destroy them.
日本鬼子我把它当球玩…
Japan is a bug waiting
to be squashed...
西方世界就等着尿裤子吧
...and the West will shake with fear.
但美国人会发射核弹
But the Americans will
send nuclear warheads.
伊卡鲁斯会给它们迎头痛击
Icarus will swat them from the sky.
你会害死我们
You will destroy us.
你会杀你亲生儿子？
You would kill your own son?
我的乖儿子早就死了
The son I knew died long ago.
爸爸…你让我失望
Father... you disappoint me.
警告，警告
Caution. Caution.
-手动驾驶
-爬高！
- Manual.
- Up!
手动驾驶
Manual.
-给我起来！
-警告
- Up! Up!
- Caution.
-手动驾驶
-求你了！
- Manual.
- Come on!
好了
Okay, guys.
Okay.
搞掂
I got it.
啧啧，找你还真不容易
把枪拿出来
My, my. You get around.
Let's see your gun.
用左手
Left hand.
是了
That's it.
丢下
Now drop it.
你已经是众叛亲离了
Looks like your friends have bailed.
打开自动驾驶
Push on autopilot.
快啊
Come on.
就这样，小朋友乖
That's it. Good girl.
嗯，水性不错嘛
Well, drowning you
didn't seem to work.
看来我得费点功夫
I'll have to try something
more to the point.
还有1000米远，越来越近了
One thousand meters and closing.
战争的艺术
你这是班门弄斧
I can read your every move.
看刀
Read this.
猪头
Bitch.
看，我们的降落伞
Look, parachutes
for the both of us.
我的降落伞
Not anymore.
要知道，邦德先生
你玩不死我
You see, Mr. Bond,
you can't kill my dreams.
我就玩死你
But my dreams can kill you.
面对命运吧
Time to face destiny.
面对地心引力吧
Time to face gravity.
我想我伤透了她的心
I think I broke her heart.
看来我们要结伴去天堂了
Looks like we're
going down together.
没那么快
Not yet.
-打开后舱门
-好
- Get the back open.
- Okay.
快！
Come on!
-快
-我说了我是w夫的命
- Come on.
- I told you I was a jinx.
其实...
I should have warned you...
大家彼此彼此
...my relationships don't last either.
至少我们有个风光大葬
At least we're gonna die rich.
快，快，快
Come on. Come on, come on.
Come on.
快
现在…
Now...
还想去天堂吗？
...you said something about
going down together?
机密档案
米兰达弗洛斯特
销案
詹姆士
James.
蒙尼潘妮
Moneypenny.
噢，詹姆士
Oh, James.
蒙尼潘妮？
Moneypenny?
我在测试
I was just testing it out.
“硬”件还不完善，是不是？
It's rather hard, isn't it?
不，“硬”就一个字！
Yes. Very.
不要，不要拿出来嘛
我还没玩够呢
Wait, don't pull it out.
I'm not finished with it yet.
瞧？大小正好合适
See? It's a perfect fit.
-留在里面
-早晚都要出来的
- Leave it in.
- It's gotta come out sooner or later.
不要，留在里面，求你了
再多几分钟好不好？
No, leave it in, please.
Few more minutes?
国有财产要缴公
We really have to get these back.
学雷锋拾金不昧，啊？
Still the good guys, huh?
那你告诉雷锋叔叔你乖不乖
I'm still not quite sure
how good you are.
我会象兔子一样乖
I am so good.
我看你象只发情的母猫一样骚
Especially when you're bad.
詹姆士邦德重出江湖
谁与争锋